<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MDoc</title>
    <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MDoc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Block quotes</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/block-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/block-quotes/</guid>
      <description>Pandoc Markdown uses email conventions for block quotes. A block quotation is one or more paragraphs or other block elements (such as lists or headings), with each line preceded by a &amp;gt; character and an optional space.
&amp;gt; This is a block quote. This &amp;gt; paragraph has two lines. &amp;gt; &amp;gt; 1. This is a list inside a block quote. &amp;gt; 2. Second item. Block quotes can contain most other Markdown elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/code/</guid>
      <description>Indented code blocks A block of text indented four spaces (or one tab) is treated as a code block. For example,
Paragraph here if (a &amp;gt; 3) { moveShip(5 * gravity, DOWN); } The initial (four space or one tab) indentation is not considered part of the verbatim text, and is removed in the output.
Fenced code blocks In addition to standard indented code blocks, you can write fenced code blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commands</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/commands/</guid>
      <description>WIP&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring MDoc</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/config/</guid>
      <description>In bigger document projects, you will have an mdoc.toml file at the root of your document. This file is meant to configure your document to look and behave the way you want. The available options are:
title (required) authors date src [build] filename [bib] csl src [style] number-sections date-format document-classe [latex] packages head title-script The title field (required) This field specifies the title of your document. It will be used for the title at the top of your generated PDF and to derive the filename of your output (unless another filename is specified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General formatting</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/formatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/formatting/</guid>
      <description>Bold and italic text To make text italic, surround it with single * or _ symbols, like this:
This text is _italicized with underscores_, and this is *italicized with asterisks*. Surrounding with double * or _ symbols, produces bold text, e.g.
This is **bold text** and __with underscores__. A * or _ character surrounded by spaces, or backslash-escaped, will not trigger emphasis:
This is * not emphasized *, and \*neither is this\*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the documentation, I will use the following terminology:
Document: A collection of files that get built into a PDF (or other forms of output). Chapter: A subdivision of a document, likely represented by a single file. To get started with a new document, run the following command
$ mdoc init &amp;#34;Awesome document&amp;#34; This will create directory named Awesome document, containing a file called mdoc.toml and a directory called src.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling your bibliography</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/bibliography/</guid>
      <description>WIP&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headings</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/headings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/headings/</guid>
      <description>There are two kinds of headings: Setext and ATX. They are equivalent, so choose the style you prefer. Both heading types can contain inline formatting or math.
ATX headers An ATX heading consists of one to six # signs and a line of text, optionally followed by any number of # signs. The number of # signs at the beginning of the line is the heading level:
## A level-two heading A paragraph or some other content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images and figures</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/images-and-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/images-and-figures/</guid>
      <description>A link immediately preceded by a ! will be treated as an image.
![](image-path.jpg) ![movie reel] [movie reel]: movie.gif ![figure caption](another-image.png) As you can see, you set the caption of the figure within the link text field. The attribute syntax is also supported on images, meaning you can define identifiers, classes and key-value pairs on images as well.
An inline ![image](foo.jpg){#id .class width=30 height=20px} and a reference ![image][ref] with attributes. [ref]: foo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/installing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/installing/</guid>
      <description>For the time being, you will have to compile MDoc yourself to install it. It is published on crates.io, so this is done easily by running
$ cargo install mdoc MDoc depends on Pandoc for parsing the Markdown content. Have a look at Installing Pandoc and make sure it is available in your PATH by running pandoc -v.
Building from source If you want to compile from upstream, clone the repo and install from path with these commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lists</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/lists/</guid>
      <description>Ordered lists To make an ordered list of items, write a decimal number, followed by a period, a space and the content you want as part of that list item.
1. one 2. two 3. three This will produce a “compact” list. If you want a “loose” list, in which each item is formatted as a paragraph, put spaces between the items:
5. one 34. two 8. three Only the first number is parsed, which means the above list will be formatted as the sequence 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/math/</guid>
      <description>Inline math Anything between two $ characters will be treated as TeX math. For an excellent reference on what is possible here, have a look at the TeX reference card.
The opening $ must have a non-space character immediately to its right, while the closing $ must have a non-space character immediately to its left, and must not be followed immediately by a digit. Thus, $20,000 and $30,000 won’t parse as math.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paragraphs</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/paragraphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/paragraphs/</guid>
      <description>A paragraph is one or more lines of text followed by one or more blank lines. Newlines are treated as spaces, so you can reflow your paragraphs as you like. Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown is strict, so if you need a hard line break, you have three options:
Use two newlines or more (essentially separating each paragraph by a blank line). This is the recommended and most readable way.
This is the first paragraph This is the second paragraph Use a backslash directly followed by a single newline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MDoc workflow</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/usage/workflow/</guid>
      <description>MDoc documents are written in Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s flavor of Markdown, with a few syntactic delights sprinkled in. If at any time you feel this markup language is limiting, you can simply write inline LaTeX or HTML and it will be parsed as expected. However, I challenge you to avoid this as much as you can to get a feel for Markdown&amp;rsquo;s refreshing simplicity, and to reassess how fancy your document really needs to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Markdown?</title>
      <link>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/why-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmaasrud.com/mdoc/markdown/why-markdown/</guid>
      <description>MDoc uses Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s flavor Markdown (with a few carefully selected additions) as it&amp;rsquo;s markup language. This choice was a simple one; the creator of Markdown, John Gruber, puts it best himself:
Markdown is intended to be as easy-to-read and easy-to-write as is feasible. Readability, however, is emphasized above all else. A Markdown-formatted document should be publishable as-is, as plain text, without looking like it’s been marked up with tags or formatting instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
